James Caddie

Contact No: 022 432 2919 — Email: james.caddie@yahoo.co.nz LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/james-caddie-314a90207

Personal Summary

Over the past 5 years, I have gained experience working on a variety of hardware systems and have had the chance to work with a wide-range of software development languages, both front-end and back-end. Due to this exposure, it has allowed me to develop a diverse tech skillset. Having worked in roles that are also customer facing, I am an excellent verbal and written communicator. I am always looking for ways to challenge myself, usually by working on interesting problems where I can get stuck in and make an impact.

Skills

- Client Relations and Support
- Project and Time Management
- Cross-Platform Proficiency (Windows, Linux)
- Software Maintenance and Updates
- System Integrity (Backups and Upgrades)
- Remote Connectivity Solutions
- Web Development Concepts (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React)
- Mobile Development Concepts (React Native, Xamarin)
- Data Interpretation and Visualization (Microsoft Power BI, Google Analytics)
- Database Architecture and Administration (MySQL & MongoDB)
- Software Prototyping and Design (Figma, Lucidchart)

Work History

Security Technician, 07/2017 to 02/2021

Aotea Security Ltd – Christchurch, Christchurch Central

- Inform customers on the correct processes to use security systems after completing tests and repairs.
- Installed various types of high-tech security systems such as access and elevator controls, alarms, and video surveillance systems.
- Servicing access control & CCTV equipment.
- Explained findings to customers and outlined repair or service options.
- Accurately completed service reports.

Security Technician, 12/2015 to 07/2017

VIP Security – Christchurch, Christchurch Central

- Installed various types of high-tech security systems such as access and elevator controls, alarms, and video surveillance systems.
- Watched both live and recorded video surveillance footage.
- Aided in displaying and exhibiting CCTV services to interested parties.
- Used diagnostic tools to identify hardware failures and replace components that were not functioning.
- Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders.

Education

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation

Currently Undertaking Level 5 UX Design Micro-credential: August 2023 – October 2023

- UX Design: Core Concepts Learn about the history, goals, role, and essential principles of user-centered design in UX.
- Design Master the design process by applying visual principles, generating innovative ideas, creating user-friendly interfaces, and implementing effective navigation patterns.
- Research Gather insights by aligning business goals with user needs, conducting thorough research, crafting user personas, and organizing information effectively.
- Testing Evaluate designs through user-focused testing, refining iteratively, guiding test sessions, and extracting valuable insights from collected data.

Whitecliffe School of Technology, Christchurch

Currently Undertaking Bachelor of Applied Information Technology: July 2023 - Present

- Event Driven Programming
- Web Programming
- Advanced Programming
- Interaction Design
- Web Technologies

Completed Diploma in Software Development: February 2022 – July 2023

- Client-side Development: Proficient in HTML/CSS and JavaScript for creating responsive websites.
- Business Analysis and Solution Design: Experienced in gathering client requirements and creating comprehensive project documentation.
- Data Structures and Algorithms: Skilled in using C# to implement various data structures and algorithms.
- Mobile Development: Designed and developed mobile apps using Figma and Xamarin Forms
- Advanced Mobile Development: Expertise in cross-platform mobile app development with React Native.
- Software Testing and Maintenance: Proficient in testing and maintaining diverse software applications.
- Application Security & Server-Side Development: Competent in developing secure web applications following standard security principles.
- Agile Project Management: Well-versed in project planning and management using Agile software development methodologies.
- Web Services: Proficient in selecting software architectures, tools, and technologies for developing solutions.
- Data Access Management: Experienced in handling digital assets and working with data access/storage technologies, including MySQL and MongoDB.

Completed Certificate in Information Technology: July – December 2021

- IT Systems (Installation of Linux and Windows OS, Basic Networking/Subnetting)
- Professional Practice (Covered basics on principles to follow within IT Industry)
- Data Handling & Web Concepts (Microsoft SQL database, HTML, CSS, and Java Script)
- Programming Principles (Basic python coding, OOP C# coding)

Completed Certificate in IT Essentials: February – July 2021

- IT Fundamentals (Assembling and Disassembly computers, Fault Finding computers, setting up a simple network devices)
- Information Management (Design/Creating relational databases using Microsoft Access.)
- Web Design (Using HTML, CSS & JavaScript to develop simple websites.)
- Software Development (Fundamentals of coding (Functions, Variables and Boolean Expressions), Creating GUI interface programs in python.)

References

References available upon request